<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Working Group on Name Change Policy Working Group</title>
    <link>/authors/twg/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Working Group on Name Change Policy Working Group</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Theme &amp;copy; 2021 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wangchucheng.com/&#34;&gt;C. Wang&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ruiqima.com/&#34;&gt;R. Ma&lt;/a&gt;
</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/authors/twg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Five Guiding Principals and Best Practices</title>
      <link>/resources/principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/principles/</guid>
      <description>Principle # 1 Name changes should be available to authors upon request without legal documentation, unnecessary barriers, burdens, or labor placed upon the author making the request.
Many publishers struggle with the extent to which such a policy should require “proof” from the requesting author, and what the burden of proof should be. Publishers raise the concern that such a policy might be exploited and allow bad actors to engage in unethical or fraudulent behavior. Such fears are not based in evidence or precedent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Press</title>
      <link>/resources/resource-press/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/resource-press/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This section includes articles on author name changes or press releases from publishers that cite our working group or individual members.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources for Authors</title>
      <link>/resources/resource-author/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/resource-author/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This section includes resources for authors: A list of publishers and journals with existing name change policies, links to articles and editorials we’ve written, as well as email templates for reaching out to publishers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources for Publishers</title>
      <link>/resources/resource-publisher/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/resource-publisher/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This section includes resources for publishers who want to introduce a name change policy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
